

☑ jlalucescareer123@gmail.com ६ (908)414-3555 ♀ Los Angeles, California

in www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-laluces 🗘 jlaluces123

SUMMARY

Junior Full Stack Web Developer who is ready to create work that has wide-ranging impacts while keeping a fresh mind when learning new technologies. Experience in web development on both front-end and back-end, creating a broad range of applications, discovering new languages and frameworks, and creating sustainable code.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JavaScript, React, Redux, Jest, HTML / CSS, SQL, SQLite, NodeJS, Express, Knex, Python, C

PROJECTS

Let's Get Tacos Feb. 2019 to Mar. 2019

- Let's Get Tacos is an event meet-up app centered around avid taco eaters who love to eat with other people of the same interest: with 4 team members, it took 5 weeks to build.
- Researched and convinced all team members that Material-UI should be used to style the application after independently creating a demo showcasing the framework.
- Created a thorough document to prevent merge conflicts, and updated the project's Trello board constantly, to accurately show the current state of the app and what needs to be done.
- Refactored 2 backend endpoints with NodeJS and Express as well as added the endpoint to implement the Stripe API feature.
- Constructed the early create-event functionality with React and Redux, as well as implemented the Stripe feature after reading through the documentation.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance · Web Developer

Mar. 2019 to Current, Mar. 2019 to Current · Remote

- Enhanced website performance by creating production-ready code which sped up load times by over 50%
- Followed best practices by using next-gen image formats and properly sizing elements
- Utilized React's component methodology to create and re-use components resulting in faster load times and less code clutter
- Replicated numerous designs and turned them into functional high quality code
- Practiced better communication to clients by giving clear deadlines and addressing issues immediately, resulting in a better experience for the client

Visual Communications · Intern

Oct. 2017 to June 2018 \cdot Los Angeles, California

- Increased exposure to film festivals by reaching out to communities through efficiently advertising and through physical communication.
- Coordinated 2 volunteer teams of 4 people in the setup process of various venues, leading to a visually stunning experience for customers.
- Enhanced company's film festival website by updating and adding 10+ article review posts to the Wordpress website, applying organization skills by keeping the Trello board up-to-date, and also learning how to manage a Wordpress website by constantly updating new information instead of delivering dead content to users.
- Increased profit from film festivals by 5%, creating visually appealing pins by collaborating with the logo designers about the specifications of the logos the company needed as well as teach other interns how to create the pins through a walkthrough document.

EDUCATION

Lambda School, Certificate in Web Development and Computer Science July 2018 to Current

Lambda School is an intensive Computer Science & Software Engineering Academy that focuses on real-world practices, taking students through a hands-on experience using an in-depth curriculum that focuses on Computer Science, Software Engineering, and Web Development.

- Learned and implemented Git branching workflow for large projects.
- Utilized an Agile development workflow during capstone project.
- Mastered curriculum in: React, Redux, Jest, Node, Express, Python, and C.
- Created production-ready code using skills in: React, Redux, Node, and Express to create multi-paged applications.